{
    "language": "Java",
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": "11",
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "What is the correct way to define a main method in Java?",
            "options": [
                "public static void main(String[] args)",
                "public main void(String[] args)",
                "static main(String[] args)"
            ],
            "answer": "public static void main(String[] args)"
        },
        {
            "id": "12",
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "What is the default value of a boolean variable in Java?",
            "options": [
                "true",
                "false",
                "null"
            ],
            "answer": "false"
        },
        {
            "id": "13",
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Which of the following is the correct extension of Java code files?",
            "options": [
                ".js",
                ".java",
                ".class"
            ],
            "answer": ".java"
        },
        {
            "id": "14",
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Which keyword is used for the block to be examined for exceptions?",
            "options": [
                "try",
                "catch",
                "check"
            ],
            "answer": "try"
        },
        {
            "id": "15",
            "type": "mcq",
            "question": "Which of the following is the numerical range of a char data type in Java?",
            "options": [
                "0 to 256",
                "0 to 65535",
                "-127 to 127"
            ],
            "answer": "0 to 65535"
        },
        {
            "id": "16",
            "type": "prog_java",
            "question": "Write a Java program that prints Hello World. If you use double quotes in your answer, be sure to use a backslash before them.",
            "input": null,
            "output": "Hello World",
            "solution": "public class HelloWorld { public static void main(String[] args) { System.out.println(\"Hello World\"); } }"
        },
        {
            "id": "17",
            "type": "prog_java",
            "question": "Write a Java program that prints the result of integer division of 100 by 3, ignoring the remainder. A single integer should be printed.",
            "input": null,
            "output": "33",
            "solution": "public class Main { public static void main(String[] args) { int a = 100; int b = 3; System.out.println(a/b); } }"
        },
        {
            "id": "18",
            "type": "prog_java",
            "question": "Write a Java program that prints the Fibonacci series up to the 10th term. The printed output should be formatted as \"0 1 2 \" and so on.",
            "input": null,
            "output": "0 1 1 2 3 5 8 13 21 34 ",
            "solution": "public class Main { public static void main(String[] args) { int n = 10, t1 = 0, t2 = 1; for (int i = 1; i <= n; ++i) { System.out.print(t1 + \" \"); int sum = t1 + t2; t1 = t2; t2 = sum; } } }"
        },
        {
            "id": "19",
            "type": "prog_java",
            "question": "Write a Java program that prints the first 10 perfect squares. The printed output should be formatted as \"0 1 2 \" and so on.",
            "input": null,
            "output": "1 4 9 16 25 36 49 64 81 100 ",
            "solution": "public class Main { public static void main(String[] args) { for (int i = 1; i <= 10; ++i) { System.out.print(i*i + \" \"); } } }"
        },
        {
            "id": "20",
            "type": "prog_java",
            "question": "Write a Java program that calculates and prints the sum of numbers from 1 to 100. A single integer should be printed.",
            "input": null,
            "output": "5050",
            "solution": "public class Main { public static void main(String[] args) { int sum = 0; for(int i = 1; i <= 100; i++) { sum += i; } System.out.println(sum); } }"
        }
    ]
}
